<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>collaborative | </title>
    <link>/tags/collaborative/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/collaborative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>collaborative</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/icon-512.png</url>
      <title>collaborative</title>
      <link>/tags/collaborative/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFIDs-macaca</title>
      <link>/project/afids-macaca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/afids-macaca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing accurate spatial correspondences across brains is a fundamental step in neuroscience research. Current methods use sophisticated algorithms to perform registrations between brains, providing a mapping between modalities, subjects, template spaces, and even different species. However, the accuracy of these mappings varies widely depending on factors such as the image quality, the registration algorithm, and its parameters. To quantify registration accuracy, a point-based set of 32 anatomical landmarks, termed anatomical fiducials (&lt;strong&gt;AFIDs&lt;/strong&gt;), has recently been described and validated for human magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) datasets (&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1002/hbm.24693&#34;&gt;Lau et al., 2019&lt;/a&gt;). The &lt;strong&gt;AFIDs-macaca&lt;/strong&gt; project seeks to bridge the gap between human and animal models in neuroscience research by extending the &lt;strong&gt;AFIDs&lt;/strong&gt; framework to a widely used non-human primate model, the macaques.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RheMAP</title>
      <link>/project/rhemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/rhemap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RheMAP project provides access to a set of pre-calculated non-linear registrations between some of the most commonly used rhesus macaque brain templates (D99, INIA19, MNI macaque, NMT, Yerkes19). The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PRIME-RE/RheMAP&#34;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt; contains the code used to calculate the registration warps and example code that demonstrates how to use the resulting warp files to remap data between different template spaces. Non-linear registration warps were generated using &lt;a href=&#34;http://stnava.github.io/ANTs/&#34;&gt;ANTs&lt;/a&gt; and can directly be downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/3668510&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;Authors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikoloz Sirmpilatze &amp;amp; P. Christiaan Klink.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRIME-RE</title>
      <link>/project/prime-re/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/prime-re/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The preprocessing and analysis of nonhuman primate (NHP) magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) data presents some unique challenges. Over the years, many laboratories and researchers have created their own custom solutions to many of these problems. PRIME-RE aims to provide an overview of the main difficulties and curate a collection of solutions that currently exist within the broader NHP-MRI community for specific processing steps that are commonly performed on NHP MRI data. Since this is a community effort, we strongly encourage you to contribute your workflows and pipelines. PRIME-RE is maintained by members of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fcon_1000.projects.nitrc.org/indi/indiPRIME.html&#34;&gt;PRIME-DE consortium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurizons</title>
      <link>/project/neurizons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/neurizons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-neurizons&#34;&gt;About Neurizons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurizons is a multidisciplinary neuroscience conference organized by the students of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gpneuro.uni-goettingen.de/&#34;&gt;International Max Planck Research School (IMPRS) for Neurosciences&lt;/a&gt;, in Göttingen. I have been part of the organizing committee since 2017 and have mainly taken care of the conference&amp;rsquo;s graphic design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurizons 2020 took place online, due to the global Covid-19 pandemic. I took part in migrating the conference into a virtual platform - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crowdcast.io/&#34;&gt;crowdcast&lt;/a&gt;. You can read about my main take-aways from this experience in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/niksirbi/status/1280875270510125056&#34;&gt;twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
